Robert F. Terrell

Pompano Beach, FL 33062 (317) 258-0488 rterrell25@gmail.com

LinkedIn: rterrell25 Website: rterrell.netlify.app GitHub: rterrell25

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience as a financial analyst. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects. Dedicated to maintaining up-to-date industry knowledge, including front/back-end web development, JavaScript, React.is, React-Apollo, React-Redux, GraphQL, GraphQL Yoga, Prisma, Node.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Angular, TypeScript, Google-Cloud-Functions, Firestore, HTML, CSS, GitHub, and agile methodologies.

EDUCATION

Indiana University

Bachelor of Liberal Studies: Social and Historical Studies

- Bachelor of Liberal Studies GPA: 3.37/4.00
- Upper Level Classes GPA: 3.59/4.00

Wyncode Coding Academy(Full-Time Program)

Curriculum:

- JavaScript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, UX/UI Collaboration, Project Management
- 350 Hours of staffed learning and writing over 5,000 lines of code

WORK EXPERIENCE

Smart Software Solutions

Front-End Developer

- Web Application automating Scrum Master position
- using technologies, such as React-Apollo, GraphQl, PostgreSQL

Team Lead

- Manage junior developers on front-end development
- Manage GitHub merge conflicts
- update user stories using agile methodologies(trello)

Wyncode Academy

Teaching Assistant/Staff Developer

- Assist students throughout 10-week coding bootcamp
- Help students to troubleshoot coding issues
- Guide and teach students through stand ups as well as Agile methodologies
- Grade homework for students

Job Tracker Team

- Web Application allowing recent Wyncode graduates to track job applications
- Utilizes Google Firestore, Google Cloud Functions, React.js, Express

BFS Capital (Small business lender with operations in the U.S., U.K., and Can.)

Perfect Audit Project Manager

- Oversaw project to automate banking operations
- Worked with tech company Ocrolus to develop rules for automated banking system
- Led testing and development phase, refining system as needed for final production
- Oversaw and approved finalized excel macro used in newly adopted operating system

Pricing Analyst

- Priced merchant applications using pricing algorithm
- Reviewed applicant financials/CCR/CBR via Experian
- Made Final decision as to whether application should be priced and placed with underwriting

UK/US Operations Support Analyst

- Reviewed all US/UK merchant bank/credit card processing statements via Microsoft Excel
- Determined annual revenue/cash flow calculations within Microsoft Excel
- Made Final decision on whether merchants met qualifications for loan/merchant cash advance

Miami, FL

Bloomington, IN

Aug. 2011-May 2016

Sept. 2019-Dec. 2019

Indianapolis, IN Nov. 2019-Present

Indianapolis, IN Nov. 2019-Present

Miami, FL

Jan. 2020-Present

Miami. FL

Feb. 2020-Present

Coral Springs, FL Mar. 2018-June 2019

Coral Springs, FL Dec. 2018-June 2019

Coral Springs, FL

Feb. 2018 - June 2019

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Odd Jobs

- Web application pairing consumers with reliable contractors
- Maintains a simplistic design that allows for a heightened user experience
- Technologies used include: React.js, PostgreSQL, Ruby on Rails, Google Maps API
- Heroku: https://oddjobs-react.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub:
 - o Front-End: https://github.com/Rterrell25/Oddjobs_React_App
 - o Back-End: https://github.com/Rterrell25/Oddjobs_Rails_API

BarHop

- Web application providing users with the top drinking places based on their location
- Users have access to detailed information about each bar as well as reviews other users have left about that location
- Technologies used include: React.js, Node.js, Javascript, Yelp API
- Heroku: https://barhop-wyncode.herokuapp.com/
- GitHub: https://github.com/Rterrell25/Bar_Hop_React_App

JobTracker

- A platform that allows recent graduates from Wyncode Academy track job applications, store resume's, and monitor follow ups
- Technologies used include: React.js, Node.js, Google Cloud Functions, and Firestore
- Netlify: https://jobtracker.netlify.app/
- GitHub: https://github.com/Rterrell25/JobTracker_Client

INDEPENDENT COURSEWORK

Udemv

- Advanced React: React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux)
- Javascript The Modern Javascript Bootcamp created by Andrew Mead
- React-Apollo The Modern GraphQL Bootcamp created by Andrew Mead
- Mern-Stack- React Node Ecommerce from scratch to deployment by Ryan Dunghel

Wes-Bos

• Advanced-React: Advanced React and GraphQL